Miami, Florida 786-955-4382

# **Miguel Ferreiro**

linkedin.com/in/mferres mferr188@fiu.edu

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I am currently earning my Computer Science degree with coursework focused on the learning various programming languages, algorithms, database management, and software testing. My experience working as application support specialist has prepared me to delve more into the field and gain experience from experts at this position. I believe I can contribute my programming knowledge in this role while preparing for my future career goal of working as a team leader of software developers helping set the direction for development on the technical level.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Florida International University (FIU)

• GPA: 3.25

• Related coursework: Software Engineering, Database Management, Theory of Algorithms, Discrete Mathematics.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming Languages:** Java, C++, C, HTML, SQL **Software:** MS Office, Excel, Adobe, Visual Studio, Netbeans

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Top Tracking System LLC**

Miami, FL

December 2022

Miami, FL

Application Support Specialist

August 2019 - Present

- Tested troubleshooting methods and devised innovative solutions.
- Responsible for working on day-to-day customer inquiries, including technical assistance, using the best use of products and service.
- Possible participation in the evaluation of new software changes while specifying application requirements.
- Assist with on-site installation and maintenance of software systems for users.

H&M

Miami, FL May 2019 – August 2019

Sales Advisor

- Worked with the management team to implement a proper division of responsibilities.
- Stocked and replenished merchandise according to the store layout.
- Operated a cash register for cash and credit card transactions with 100% accuracy.

#### AWARDS/HONORS

## Dean's List, College of Engineering and Computing

2020 - Present

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS

#### Languages

EnglishSpanish

## Leadership

- Guided other students as project leader in developing class projects.
- Mentored new employees at workplace and filled management position when needed.

## Critical thinking

- Made quick decisions on a daily basis to resolve clients' technical issues.
- Applied data structures knowledge in school assignments to arrive at best time complexity.